when you're building applications you
want them to deliver a great experience
for your users maybe you want your
application to generate in-app purchase
options during a gaming session rapidly
validate street address updates or make
image thumbnails available instantly
after a user uploads photos to make this
magic happen your application needs
back-end code that runs in response to
events like image uploads in app
activity website clicks or sensor
outputs but managing the infrastructure
to host and execute back-end code
requires you to size provision and scale
a bunch of servers manage operating
system updates apply security patches
and then monitor all this infrastructure
for performance and availability
wouldn't it be nice if you could just
focus on building great applications
without having to spend lots of time
managing servers introducing AWS lambda
AWS lambda is a compute service that
runs your back-end code in response to
events such as object uploads to Amazon
s3 buckets updates to Amazon DynamoDB
tables data and Amazon Kinesis dreams or
in-app activity once you upload your
code to lambda the service handles all
the capacity scaling patching and
administration of the infrastructure to
run your code and provides visibility
into performance by publishing real-time
metrics and logs to Amazon Cloud Watch
all you need to do is write the code AWS
lambda is very low cost and does not
require any upfront investment when you
use AWS lambda you're simply charged a
low fee per request and for the time
your code runs measured in increments of
100 milliseconds getting started with
AWS lambda is easy there are no new
languages tools or frameworks to learn
you can use any third-party library even
native ones the code you run on AWS
lambda is called a lambda function you
just upload your code as a zip file or
design it in the integrated development
environment in the AWS management
console or you can select from a list of
function samples pre-built for common
use cases
image conversion file compression and
change notifications and built-in
support for the AWS SDK makes it easy to
call other AWS services once your
function is loaded you select the event
source to monitor such as an Amazon s3
bucket or Amazon DynamoDB table and
within a few seconds lambda will be
ready to trigger your function
automatically when an event occurs with
lambda any event can trigger your
function making it easy to build
applications that respond quickly to new
information to learn more about AWS
lambda visit our website and you can get
your first lambda function up and
running with a few clicks in the AWS
management console and with the AWS free
tier you can try lambda for free